The Adorable Lorax Speaks For The Trees In This
Music-Filled Tale That’s Certain To Please!
The Lorax is a animation, family, tv movie film directed by Hawley Pratt.
The Once-ler, a ruined industrialist, tells the tale of his rise to wealth and subsequent fall, as he disregarded the
warnings of a wise old forest creature called the Lorax about the environmental destruction caused by his greed.
Narrator, played by Eddie Albert.
The Lorax / The Once-ler (voice), played by Bob Holt.
Miss O'Schmunsler (voice), played by Athena Lorde.
Boy (voice), played by Harlen Carraher.
Singer, played by Scatman Crothers.
Singer, played by Vivian Vance.
The Lorax is a musical Dr.
Seuss animated short produced by DePatie–Freleng Enterprises which first aired as a television special on CBS
in the United States on February 14, 1972, and in Canada on CBC Television on October 22, 1972.
The special was written by Theodor Geisel (Dr.
Seuss), based on his 1971 book of the same name.
The film explores themes of pollution, harmony, based on
children's book, nature, corporate greed.